快跑
Run!
狗
Dog!
不  不
No! No!
放开它
Let him go.
我说了放开它
I said let him go.
我从没想过会再见到你
I never thought I'd see you again.
我也是
Yeah, I thought the same.
你在这里干什么
What're you doing out here?
你一个人吗
You alone?
你看我有同伴吗
You see anybody with me?
我在路上看见你和其他人一起
I saw you out on the road with the others.
他们是谁
Who are they?
你是他们的一员吗
You one of them?
我在路上碰到了一小队人
Crossed a small group on the road.
不  我不是他们的一员
No. I ain't one of them.
我独来独往  一向如此
I travel light, like always.
我们要走了  走吧  小子
We're gonna go. Come on, boy.
走吧
Come on.
-真有趣  -什么有趣
- Well, that's funny. - What's funny?
我一直以为它更喜欢你
I always thought he liked you better.
我不知道你在跟谁战斗
Look, I don't know who you're fighting,
但那与我无关
but I am not part of it.
我们要走了  走吧
We're going. Come on!
行尸走肉
第十一季  第四集
我们来看看你是否是对的
Let's see if you're right.
我为你回去了
I came back for you.
我曾到处找你
I looked everywhere for you.
很抱歉你和这些人沦落到了一起
I'm sorry you ended up with these people.
这些人是我的家人
These people are my family.
他们可没有停止找我
They never stopped looking for me.
当他们找到我时  我回家了
When they found me, I came home.
你的家人呢  达里尔
How about your family, Daryl?
你跟我说过的那些家人
The ones you told me about?
他们就是路上的那些人吗
That who was out on the road?
很久以前  我的家人惹错了人
My family picked the wrong fight with the wrong people a long time ago.
就像我跟你说的  我独自一人
It's like I told you, I'm alone.
你真脏
You're filthy.
抬起来
Up.
再问一次
Again!
其他人
The others.
他们还在外面吗
Are they still out there?
他们在附近吗
Are they close?
我不知道
I don't know.
谁是首领
Who's the leader?
是那个女人吗
Is it the woman?
我不是他们的人
I ain't one of them.
胡扯
Bullshit.
够了
Enough.
肖
Shaw?
我说了停下
I said stop.
我来对付他
I'll handle him.
他会开口的  只需要再给我一点时间
He'll crack. I just need a little more time.
我已经给你足够时间了
I've given you enough time already.
我说了抬起来
I said up!
我需要你配合
I need you to cooperate.
我跟你交代了一切
I told you everything.
你什么都没说
You told us nothing.
说
Talk.
我们的上司可没这么好说话
The one we answer to won't be so nice.
我和他们做过交易
I traded with them.
他们给了我些食物
They gave me some food.
我帮忙搬些东西
I hauled some gear.
我和他们认识还不到一星期
I knew them less than a week.
来啊  你可以杀了我
Go ahead, kill me if you want.
我没什么别的可说了
I got nothing else to say.
我们就不该把他带回来
Should've never brought him back.
我知道自己在干什么
I know what I'm doing.
可不  你一直这么说
Yeah, you keep saying that.
达里尔
Daryl?
是你吗
Is that you?
其他人呢  他们还好吗
The others? Are they okay?
我不知道你的朋友们在哪
I don't know where your friends are.
我也不在乎
I don't care, neither.
-但是...  -没什么可但是的
- But I -- - But nothing.
我们不过是分享过食物而已
Just 'cause we shared a bag of grain
这不意味着我在乎你们
does not make me give a shit about you.
听明白了吗
Understand?
无论你们和这帮人有什么过节
Whatever beef you have with these people,
我都不想掺和
I want no part of it.
听见了吗
You hear me?
你最好闭上嘴  别来烦我
You need to shut up and leave me alone.
懂了吗
Got it?
懂了
I got it, yeah.
我没看错你
I was right about you.
当初就应该让你饿着
Shoulda let you starve.
王八蛋
Asshole.
我一个字都不会透露给你们的
I ain't telling you bastards a thing.
起来  起来
Get up. Get up!
放开我
Let me go!
和从前一样固执
Just as stubborn as ever.
你就是这么认为的吗
Is that what you think this is?
我固执
Me being stubborn?
好吧
Fine.
是坚韧
Hard-headed.
你得把真相告诉我
You need to tell me the truth.
我从来没有骗过你
I've never lied to you.
从来没有  莉娅
Never, Leah.
现在也不会
I'm not gonna start now.
我们再试一遍
Let's try this again.
关于那群人  你都了解些什么
What do you know about those people?
我什么都不了解
I don't know shit.
如果我可以  我肯定会帮你
I'd help you if I could.
你知道我会的
You know I would.
把狗还给我  放我走吧
Just give me Dog, let me go,
你再也不会见到我了
you'll never see me again.
这就是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
怎么了
What is it?
找到博西了
Found Bossie.
特纳呢
And Turner?
我努力过了  但没能救他
I tried. I couldn't save him.
-我努力过了  -没关系  孩子
- I tried. - It's okay, son.
你做了正确的事
You did the right thing.
你把他带回家了
You brought him home.
主啊  我们把兄弟特纳交给你
Lord, we release our brother Turner to you.
请您拥紧他
Please, hold him close.
以主之名  阿门
In your name, oh Lord, amen.
阿门
Amen.
上帝在此
God is here.
他很愤怒
He's angry.
我很愤怒
I'm angry.
你们感受到了吗
Do you feel that?
去让他们感受到我们的怒火
Go make them feel our wrath.
怎么了
What happened?
我有一个兄弟死了
One of my brothers is dead.
他叫迈克尔·特纳
Michael Turner was his name.
我们曾在世界各地并肩战斗
We fought all over the world together.
我们最后一次驻扎回来后  教皇将他纳入麾下
Pope brought him in after our last tour,
那时他刚创办公司
when he started his company.
我以为你们是士兵
I thought you were soldiers.
我们曾经是
We were.
之后私营化了
Then we went private.
你之前没告诉过我你是佣兵
You didn't tell me you were a merc.
这重要吗
Mm, does it matter?
都是一样的工作
I mean, it's the same damn job.
只是我们真能付得起生活费了
Except we could actually pay our bills.
迈克尔跟我很像  他也没有家人
Michael was like me, you know? He didn't have a family.
他就是我没能拥有的弟弟
He was the little brother I never had.
我一直想要的弟弟
You know, the little brother I always wanted.
现在他死了
And he's dead.
我们在这里失去过很多同伴
You know, we lost a lot of people...
一直很艰难
here, and it's been hard.
但这次不一样
Not like this.
这是我
This is the first time
很长时间以来第一次失去了亲近的人
I've lost someone close to me in a long time.
好吧
Well...
或许除了你
except maybe for you.
你那时并没失去我
You didn't lose me.
我回去找过你  但你走了
I came back and you were gone.
你离开了我
You left me.
我问你你想要什么
I asked you what you wanted.
你就走了
You left.
我害怕了
I got scared.
怕什么
Of what?
放手
Letting go.
无所谓了  反正我们也不会有结果
It doesn't matter. It wouldn't have worked anyway.
不可能拥有幸福
Couldn't have been happy.
在这样一个世界里不可能
Not in a world like this.
这是你的想法还是你家人的
Is that you talking or your family?
难道你就没做过坏事吗
Like you've never done things?
杀人
Killed people.
我知道你做过什么
I know the things you've done.
你没权利指责我  根本没有
You have no right to judge, not at all.
这就是真正的我  达里尔
This is me, Daryl.
不论是好的还是坏的
The good and the bad.
全都是我  一直如此
All of it. It always has been.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
那我也没办法
Well, I can't help with that.
但我可以帮你救自己
But I can help you save yourself.
因为不管怎样  我仍在乎你
Because despite everything, I still care about you,
我不希望你发生不好的事
and I don't want anything bad to happen to you.
所以你必须交代点什么
So, you need to tell me something.
任何事都行
Anything.
如果你不说  我就控制不了我的指挥官
'Cause if you can't, I can't control my commander
以及他的下一步行动
or what he will do next.
特纳的死令他愤怒不已
He's angry about Turner,
他要找人付出代价
and he wants someone to pay.
有个女人
There's a woman.
她是首领
She's the leader.
他们用暗语交流  因为我是外人
They were speaking in code 'cause I was an outsider.
有一个高瘦的男人
There was a tall, skinny guy.
是个话痨
Never shuts up.
还有个背着猎枪的神父
And a priest who carries a shotgun.
那是他们的领导层吗
That's their leadership?
是的  但他们有人数优势
Yeah. But they have the numbers.
其中一个士兵说漏嘴了
And one of their soldiers slipped up,
他要去找他们那三十几个战士
and he was gonna go meet three dozen of their fighters.
比你这里的十五个士兵多得多
That's way more than the 15 you got here.
看来你被关在这也没闲着
Well, you've been doing your work down here, huh?
我今晚会叫人把你放出来
I'll have you moved out of here tonight.
这样你能舒服些
so you can be more comfortable.
我何时能见到他
When do I meet him?
教皇
This Pope?
快了
Soon.
你说得对
Well, you were right.
他很难降服
He was hard to break.
他告诉我  敌人比我们想象中要多得多
He told me there are a lot more out there than we thought.
比我们这里的人数多两倍以上
More than twice the force we have in here.
我认为他适合这里
I think he'll be good here.
而且我们需要人手
And we need the manpower,
特纳死了
with Turner gone
尼科尔斯和蒙塔尼奥仍下落不明
and Nicholls and Montanio still missing.
说句话
Say something.
我知道我讨厌你这样做
You know I hate it when you do this.
做什么
Do what?
晾着我
Freeze me out.
一切不是围着你转的  莉娅
Not everything is about you, Leah.
我从没这样说过
I never said it was.
是吗
Oh, no?
因为我们在这里
'Cause here we are.
浪费了一天追踪敌人的时间  只因为你
Losing a day of tracking our enemy 'cause you --
你要对老男友进行希望渺茫的审问
you had to go on a fishing expedition with an old boyfriend.
继续吧
So, go on, then.
告诉我
Tell me.
你查到想查的事了吗
You find what you're looking for?
我说过他有用  我说对了
I told you he would be useful, and I was right.
他很像我们
He's a lot like us.
他不怕痛苦  他不怕死亡
Pain doesn't scare him, death doesn't scare him.
卡弗看到了
Carver saw it.
拜托  你也看到了
Come on, you see it.
我只看到了一个想上你的男人
I just see a guy who wants to get in your pants.
好吧
Fine.
他是忍不住盯着他所爱过的人
Who couldn't stop gazing at somebody he loved.
我没说过他爱过我
I never said he loved me.
你今天本可以在外面杀了他
You could've ended him out there today,
而你没下手
and you didn't.
为什么
Why?
他曾对我有所意义
At one point, he meant something to me, yeah.
我对此没有隐瞒
I've been open about that.
但在你找到了我  我选择了这个大家庭的那天
But it ended the day you found me
这一切就结束了
and I chose this family,
我从没有后悔过做出那个决定
and I have never once regretted that decision,
我也不希望你后悔
and I don't want you to, either.
你后悔吗
Do you?
我更相信你
I believe in you.
相比其他人来说
More than the others.
我知道
I know.
你觉得我们可以信任他吗
You think we can trust him?
可以
Yeah.
好
Good.
让我亲眼看看
Now, let me see for myself.
有话要说吗
You got something to say?
说吧  别害羞
Come on, man. Don't be shy.
你就要见老大了
You're about to meet the man.
这怂样留给你女友吧
Yeah, save that coy shit for your girlfriend.
肖才不是谁的女友
Aww, Shaw ain't nobody's girlfriend.
我敢打赌这小子什么都听她的
I'm betting she wears the pants with homeboy here.
你说是不是
Isn't that right?
你屁都不懂  卡弗  闭嘴吧
You don't know shit about shit, Carver. Knock it off.
那我还是出去吧
I guess I'll just show my dumb ass out, then.
教皇快来了
Pope is on his way.
在我见他之前  你想提醒我什么吗
Anything you wanna tell me about this guy before I meet him?
看我眼色行事
Just follow my lead.
给  拿着
Here! Take it! Take it!
用这个
Here! Here!
快
Come on.
由火铸就
Forged by fire.
由神指定
Ordained by God.
欢迎他
Welcome him!
赴汤蹈火
Fortitudo Saludis!
出自《圣经》拉丁语版钦定本诗篇140:8
指上帝在争战之中赐予我勇气
你信上帝吗
You believe in God?
不信
No. No, I don't.
不再信了
Not anymore.
我现在只信自己
Guess I just believe in me now.
这是个错误
Well, that's a mistake.
-为何  -因为你不是上帝
- Why's that? - 'Cause you're not Him.
我通过了你的小测试
I passed your little test, didn't I?
无论你怎么称呼那事
Whatever you want to call it.
你以为这就结束了吗
Oh, and you think that's the end of it?
你还想要我做什么
What else do you want from me?
我想要
I want...
我想要你理解
I want you to understand.
坐
Sit down.
我们都是在死亡谷认识的
We all met in the Valley of Death.
反正我们是这样称呼那里的
That's what we call it, anyway.
阿富汗的山区
Hills of Afghanistan.
我们为国奋战
We fought for our country,
把阵亡的战友抬下战场
carried our fallen brothers off the field.
抬了太多人  后来我们都数不清了
Carried so many, we lost count after a while.
政客们
Politicians.
只管开支票
They wrote the checks.
根本不在乎我们
We weren't anything to them.
我们只是道具
Just props.
下次竞选所用的道具
Props for their next campaign.
他们喜欢谈论上帝
See, they -- they talked about God.
他们不认识上帝
They didn't know God.
他们没见过他的脸
They never saw His face.
不像我们
It's not like we did.
我们看到上帝无处不在
We saw God everywhere.
他在鲜血  恐怖和死亡之中
He was in the blood and the horror and death.
他在那  为我们指引方向
He was there, telling us where to go.
在那段日子里  我们唯有指望他
Didn't have much else to hold on to in those days but Him.
还有彼此
And each other.
你抽烟吗
You smoke?
那场战争差点永远废了我们
That war damn near ruined all of us for good.
回国之后  我的部下都有永久性损伤
Came home and my guys had permanent injuries.
他们睡不着觉  找不到正经工作
They couldn't sleep. They couldn't find real jobs.
所以
So...
我们成了人们口中的佣兵
people called us mercenaries.
那些没人想做的脏活累活
We did all the ugly, dirty work
都由我们来做
nobody else wanted to do.
还拿到了丰厚的佣金
Got paid for it, too. Handsomely.
真正的脏活是在沦陷之后开始的
The real dirty work started after the Fall.
我从没有经历过那样的战争
Never been in a war like that.
从没有见过那样的混乱
Never seen that kind of chaos,
而我以前什么都见过
and I had seen everything.
但这个
But this...
我们做的那些事
Oh, the things we did.
所有的死亡  日复一日
All that death, day after day after day...
不久以后  我和你有了同样的想法
After a while, I started to feel like you.
我在想  上帝哪去了
Wondering -- Wondering where God was.
直到他再次现身
Until He showed His face again.
政客们  还有最后一场仗要打
See, politicians -- they had one last war to get behind.
这一次  敌人是我们
This time, coming for us.
炸弹如暴雨般落下
The bombs came thick and fast.
一直没有停
It did not stop.
我们和一些战友走散了
We lost some of our own,
不得不穿越大火去救他们
had to run through the fire to save them.
我们在城镇边缘找到了一座小教堂
Found this little church at the edge of town,
我们躲在那里  看着一切
and we holed up there as everything --
我是说所有的一切  在身边燃烧
and I mean everything -- burned around us.
等火终于熄灭了
When the fires finally died down,
我看向我的部下
I looked at my people...
我简直不敢相信
I could not believe it.
没留一滴血
Not a trace of blood.
没有烧伤
No burn marks.
连擦伤都没有
Not even a scratch.
那时我就知道了
And that's when I knew.
我们是天选之人
We were the Chosen Ones.
这些人
These men --
火焰伤不了这些人的身躯
These men upon whose bodies the fire had no power.
上帝今晚选中了你
God chose you tonight.
你毫发无伤  活着逃出了火场
I mean, you -- you came out of that fire alive and whole.
看看你  现在坐在这里
And look at you now, sitting right here.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
被烧到了吗
Any burns?
有擦伤吗
A scratch?
我以前经历过更糟的事
I've been through worse before.
你饿吗
Are. You. Hungry?
你说得对
You were right.
关于这家伙
About this one.
我当然对了
Of course I was.
分他点  博西
Give him some, Bossie.
别太贪
Don't be greedy.
他现在是家人了
He's family now.
你知道他做了什么吧
You know what he did, don't you?
他背着死去的兄弟走了10英里
He walked 10 miles with his dead brother on his back.
10英里
10 miles.
这需要多大的力量啊
The strength that took...
你知道我们有多感激吗
You have any idea how grateful we are?
特纳会有一个体面的葬礼
Turner will have a proper burial.
我只是做了我们都会做的事
Just did what any one of us would've done.
还疼吗
These still hurt?
需要什么吗
You need anything?
我只想问一个问题
I just have one question.
好
S-Sure.
有件事我一直很困惑
Something's been bothering me.
你的伤口
Your wounds...
在背上
are on your back.
教皇  今天已经够辛苦了
Pope, it's been a rough day.
我只是想弄清楚  肖
Just getting clarity, Shaw.
特纳被袭击时  你在哪里
Where were you when Turner was being attacked?
我在现场  我给你说过了
I-I was right there, just like I told you.
面朝敌人吗
Facing the enemy?
对
Yeah.
他受的苦够多了
He's been through enough.
害怕了会跑是人的本能反应
Human nature is to run when you are scared.
你懂的吧
You know what that's like, right?
直面恐惧需要非凡的勇气
It takes divine strength to face your fear head-on.
为别人赌上一切
Risk everything for someone else.
我们都看到了你所做的事
We all saw what you did.
先把肖救出火场  你也感受到了吧
Getting Shaw out of the fire first, and you felt it, huh?
为了保护你  他愿意做到什么地步
How far he would go just to keep you safe.
今天  上帝用火洗礼了你
Today, God baptized you in that fire.
让你成了我们的一员
Made you one of us.
不过
You see...
我忘了告诉你一件事
there's one thing I forgot to tell you.
永远不要背弃你的兄弟
Never turn your back on your brother.
上帝不只用火来洗礼
God doesn't only use fire as His baptism.
他也用火来表达愤怒
It's also His wrath.
我们是天选之人
We are the Chosen Ones!
我们奔向战场
We run into the battle.
我们奔入火场
We run into the fire.
永远如此
Always.